<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<documents>
  <document>
    <docID>Tethys_Factbook</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>FACTBOOK :: Tethys

Introduction
Background: 
Tethys is very modern, economic leader with a large population and a key member of Europe's economic, political, and defense organizations. Additionally, Tethys is a leader of environmental concerns and a party to many environmental treaties. Tethys formerly held minor colonies in Sub-Saharan Africa all of which gained independence by the middle 1960�s with a sizable minority of the Tethan population coming from former colonies. With a commitment to equality and fighting income disparity, Tethys has some of the highest tax rates in the Europe. 
Geography
Location:
Western Europe, bordering the Mediterranean Sea, between France and Italy
Maritime claims:
Territorial sea: 12 nm
Contiguous zone: 24 nm
Exclusive economic zone: 200 nm (does not apply to the Mediterranean)
Continental shelf: 200 m depth or to the depth of exploitation
Climate:
Mild winters and hot summers along the Mediterranean; cold winters and mild summers in northern mountainous region
Terrain:
Flat plains along coastline, rolling central hills; remainder is mountainous
Elevation extremes:
Lowest point: Mediterranean Sea 0 m
Highest point: Mount Belantonna 2079 m
Natural resources:
Natural gas, coal, iron ore, bauxite, timber, fish
Land use:
Arable land: 34.3%	
Permanent crops: 1.95%
Other: 64.75%
Irrigated land:
Total: 13210 sq km
Environment current issues:
Some forest damage from acid rain; some air pollution from industrial and vehicle emissions; water pollution from urban wastes, agricultural runoff
Environment international agreements:
Party to: Air Pollution, Air Pollution-Nitrogen Oxides, Air Pollution-Persistent Organic Pollutants, Air Pollution-Sulfur 85, Air Pollution-Sulfur 94, Air Pollution-Volatile Organic Compounds, Biodiversity, Climate Change, Climate Change-Kyoto Protocol, Desertification, Endangered Species, Hazardous Wastes, Law of the Sea, Marine Dumping, Marine Life Conservation, Ozone Layer Protection, Ship Pollution, Tropical Timber 83, Tropical Timber 94, Wetlands
Signed, but not ratified: none of the selected agreements
People and Society
Nationality:
Noun: Tethan (s)
Adjective: Tethan
Ethnic groups:
Greek, Celtic and Latin with Teutonic and Spanish minorities
Languages:
Tethan (official) 100%
Population:
32,975,805 (July 2013 est.)
Age structure:
0-14 years: 18.7% 
15-24 years: 11.9% 
25-54 years: 38.9% 
55-64 years: 12.6% 
65 years and over: 17.9% 
Median age:
Total: 40.6 years
Male: 39.1 years
Female: 42.1 years (2013 est.)
Major urban areas population:
CENTRUM (capital) 5.25M; Selale 845,000; Caglayan 714,000 (2012)
Economy
Economy overview:
The Tethan economy is effectively diversified across all sectors. With mountains and beaches, Tethys attracts many millions of foreign tourists behind only France. The leaders of Tethys are committed to capitalism, but also social equality through laws, tax policies, and social spending to help reduce income disparity. As a result, Tethys has some of the highest tax rates throughout Europe. 
GDP composition, by sector of origin:
Agriculture: 8.6%
Industry: 29%
Services: 62.4%
Agriculture products:
Olives, olive oil, wine grapes and citrus; lamb, goats and sheep; dairy and cheese
Industries:
Aircraft, electronics, food processing, tourism, natural gas
Labor force:
20,412,023 (2013 est.)
Labor force by occupation:
Agriculture: 10.8%
Industry: 21.3%
Services: 68.9% (2011)
Unemployment rate:
7.8% (2012 est.)
Population below poverty line:
5.8% (2012 est.)
Military:
Military branches:
Army (Army of the Land; includes Marines, Foreign Legion, Army Light Aviation), Navy, Air Force
Military service age and obligation:
18-40 years of age for male and female voluntary military service; no conscription; 1-year service obligation; women serve in noncombat posts (2013)
Manpower available for military service:
Males age 18-40: 7,242,572
Females age 18-40: 7,081,316 (2011 est.)
Transnational Issues:
Disputes international:
None
Illicit drugs:
Transshipment point for South American cocaine, Southwest Asian heroin, and European synthetics; money-laundering site for narcotics trafficking organizations and organized crime</docText>
    <Location>Europe</Location>
    <Location>France</Location>
    <Location>Italy</Location>
    <Location>lamb</Location>
    <Location>Mediterranean Sea</Location>
    <Location>Mediterranean)</Location>
    <Location>Mediterranean;</Location>
    <Location>Mild</Location>
    <Location>Mount Belantonna</Location>
    <Location>northern mountainous</Location>
    <Location>Western Europe</Location>
    <Location>Wetlands</Location>
    <Organization>Air Force</Organization>
    <Organization>Air Pollution</Organization>
    <Organization>Army</Organization>
    <Organization>Army Light Aviation</Organization>
    <Organization>Biodiversity, Climate Change</Organization>
    <Organization>Celtic</Organization>
    <Organization>CENTRUM</Organization>
    <Organization>Contiguous zone</Organization>
    <Organization>Continental shelf</Organization>
    <Organization>Foreign Legion</Organization>
    <Organization>Greek</Organization>
    <Organization>Navy</Organization>
    <Organization>Noun</Organization>
    <Organization>Ozone Layer Protection</Organization>
    <Organization>Sea, Marine Dumping, Marine Life Conservation</Organization>
    <Organization>South American</Organization>
    <Organization>Southwest Asian heroin</Organization>
    <Organization>Sub-Saharan Africa</Organization>
    <Organization>Teutonic</Organization>
    <Organization>Tropical</Organization>
    <Person>bauxite</Person>
    <Person>GDP</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>Kronos_Factbook</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>FACTBOOK :: Kronos 
Introduction
Background:
Kronos was variously settled by the peoples of the Levant as far back as the Phoenicians, but avoided attempts at colonization by the British and French. The island�s economy has been dominated by three main industries. Agriculture has long dominated the local economy with most Kronisians supporting themselves through small-scale farming. Recently the timber industry has taken off; however, deforestation is a real threat. With the discovery of massive natural gas fields in 1994, the Kronisian economy has been booming. Despite the recent economic boom, many people still face deep poverty.   
Geography
Location:
Middle East, island in the Mediterranean Sea, north of Egypt
Maritime claims:
Territorial sea: 12 nm
Contiguous zone: 24 nm
Continental shelf: 200 m depth or to the depth of exploitation
Climate:
Temperate; Mediterranean with hot dry summers and cool winters
Terrain:
Northern plain with mountains to the south 
Elevation extremes:
Lowest point: Mediterranean Sea 0 m
Highest point: Mount Bouvo 1544 m
Natural resources:
Natural gas, copper, pyrites, timber, salt, arable land
Land use:
Arable land: 29.3%
Permanent crops: 5.4%
Other: 65.3%
Irrigated land:
45 sq km
Environment current issues:
Natural gas pollution water and soil; has suffered serious damage from hyper acidic substrate removal; loss of arable land; deforestation
Environment international agreements:
Party to: Biodiversity, Desertification, Endangered Species, Law of the Sea, Ozone Layer Protection
Signed, but not ratified: none of the selected agreements

Geography note:
The Tiskele River runs north from its headwaters in the Notios Mountain Range.
People and Society
Nationality:
Noun: Kronisian(s)
Adjective: Kronisian
Ethnic groups:
Kronisian (descendants of ancient Egyptians, Carthaginians, and Phoenicians with strong elements of other Mediterranean stock)
Languages:
Kronisian (official)
Population:
783,305 (July 2013 est.)
Age structure:
0-14 years: 34.5%
15-24 years: 22.3%
25-54 years: 30.4%
55-64 years: 5.6%
65 years and over: 7.2%
Median age:
Total: 20.2
Male: 19.7 
Female: 20.7
Major urban areas population:
ABILA (capital) 233,900 (2011)
Economy
Economy overview:
Kronos traditionally an agrarian culture has pivoted toward energy, specifically natural gas and financial services. As a result of corruption and poor government planning, many Kronisians have struggled to make the transition with unemployment hovering around 24% and 70% at or below the poverty line. 
GDP composition, by sector of origin:
Agriculture: 34.6%
Industry: 43%
Services: 22.4%
Agriculture � products:
Timber, fish, citrus, vegetables, grapes, olives; poultry, pork, lamb, goats; dairy, cheese
Industries:
Natural gas, wood, paper, ship building and repair, tourism, financial services
Labor force:
462,149 (2013 est.)
Labor force � by occupation:
Agriculture: 70%
Industry: 10%
Services: 20%
Unemployment rate:
23.7% (2012 est.)
Population below poverty line:
70% (2011 est.)
Military:
Military branches:
Armed Forces of Kronos (AFK; includes land, maritime, and air elements)
Military service age and obligation:
18 years of age for compulsory military service; both sexes are obligated to military service; conscript service obligation � 24 months for enlisted men and enlisted women
Manpower available for military service:
Males age 18-49: 175,534
Females age 18-49: 172,047
Transnational Issues
Disputes � international:
None
Illicit drugs:
A transshipment point for heroin and hashish to Europe; despite a strengthening of anti-money-laundering legislation, remains vulnerable to money laundering; corruption is a major concern; reporting of suspicious transactions in offshore sector remains week (2010)</docText>
    <Location>AFK</Location>
    <Location>and</Location>
    <Location>Egypt</Location>
    <Location>Europe</Location>
    <Location>island</Location>
    <Location>Kronisian</Location>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>lamb</Location>
    <Location>Mediterranean Sea</Location>
    <Location>Mediterranean stock</Location>
    <Location>Mediterranean with</Location>
    <Location>north</Location>
    <Location>note:</Location>
    <Location>Sea</Location>
    <Location>The island</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Organization>ABILA</Organization>
    <Organization>Armed Forces</Organization>
    <Organization>Carthaginians, and Phoenicians</Organization>
    <Organization>Contiguous zone</Organization>
    <Organization>Continental shelf</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronisian
Ethnic</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronisian(s</Organization>
    <Organization>Middle East</Organization>
    <Organization>Mount</Organization>
    <Organization>Northern</Organization>
    <Organization>Notios Mountain Range</Organization>
    <Organization>Noun</Organization>
    <Organization>Temperate</Organization>
    <Organization>the Phoenicians</Organization>
    <Person>GDP</Person>
    <Person>Kronisian</Person>
    <Person>Kronos</Person>
    <Person>Levant</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Peaceful Engagement</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>History of the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps Analysis Brief
By Fredrick N. Wagner and Westley B. Andrews
January 2009

A Time of Peaceful Engagement and Recruitment (2002-2004)
Elian Karel�s dynamic leadership and charismatic personality energized the remaining POK members.  Karel recognized that the POK needed to expand its membership if it were to survive and he focused his efforts on recruiting additional members in Abila.  Karel staged numerous peaceful environmental rallies and spent considerable energy working the crowds.  When not planning or working the rallies, Karel spent his time meeting with many of the social and environmental activist groups in the capitol city.  He proved to be a persuasive recruiter and many small activist groups joined forces with the POK.
Frustrated by a lack of government engagement during this time, Karel shifted the POK�s mission to include concern over government accountability and corruption.  This additional focus aligned with popular concerns of bribery and fraud, and won Karel additional supporters.</docText>
    <Location>Abila.</Location>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>Westley</Location>
    <Organization>Karel</Organization>
    <Organization>POK.</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps</Organization>
    <Person>Elian Karel</Person>
    <Person>Fredrick N. Wagner</Person>
    <Person>Karel</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Leaders</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>History of the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps Analysis Brief
By Fredrick N. Wagner and Westley B. Andrews
January 2009

Profile of Dominant POK Personalities (2009)
Elian Karel
Current leader of the POK, Karel is a dynamic speaker whose charismatic leadership abilities have won him a substantial group of loyal supporters.  The POK continues to grow in size under Karel�s leadership.  His growing popularity with the citizens of Kronos and certain media organizations is likely to gain interest in the POK agenda among General Assembly members.

Silvia Marek
Marek was the leader and co-founder of a small environmental activist group, Save Our Wildlands, which formed at the University of Abila in 1998.  Elian Karel recruited Marek and her group to join the POK in 2005.  Marek is a charismatic speaker with a passion for environmental awareness and the vegan lifestyle.  She believes persistent, peaceful protest will eventually gain the POK the necessary political influence to finally address the environmental contamination stemming from years of unrestricted gas drilling at the Tiskele Bend fields.  Marek has organized several peaceful POK rallies in Abila and is seen among the POK members as a leader, although she is not as widely respected throughout the group as Karel.

Mandor Vann
Mandor Vann, uncle to Isia and Juliana Vann, has been with the POK since retiring from the Kronos military in 2004.  Vann, who was an enlisted linguist, spent much of his military career serving at the Kronosian embassies in Tethys and Asteria.  As the POK member with the most experience in government, Vann has become the group�s top political strategist.  POK members have great respect for Vann and describe him as intense, intelligent, organized, and ambitious.

Isia Vann
Isia Vann, an Elodis native, is the older brother of Juliana Vann, the 10-year-old girl who died in 1998 after an illness related to drinking contaminated water from the Tiskele River, and nephew to Mandor Vann.  Isia is one of several POK members who advocate for a more forceful approach to gaining attention to the plight of people living downstream of Tiskele Bend.  He has been arrested several times for civil disobedience and trespassing during POK rallies.

Lucio Jakab
Lucio Jakab was a member and co-founder of a small environmental activist group, Save Our Wildlands, which formed at the University of Abila in 1998.  Elian Karel convinced Jakab and the other members of Save Our Wildlands to join forces with the POK in 2005.  Jakab is an activist who believes that the habitat of wild life unique to Kronos is imperiled by drilling, logging, and pollution.  A media communications professional, Jakab is responsible for many of the handbills, signs, banners, and slogans used by the POK.

Lorenzo Di Stefano
Lorenzo Di Stefano is a professor of environmental science at the University of Abila and a POK activist who believes that the government needs to enact stronger environmental laws to protect the country�s agrarian lifestyle.  Di Stefano has recently authored several scientific articles on the environmental contamination associated with the Hyper Acidic Substrate Removal (HASR) technique used at several Kronosian gas fields and has advocated for regulations that would outlaw this technique.</docText>
    <Location>Abila</Location>
    <Location>Asteria.</Location>
    <Location>Isia</Location>
    <Location>Karel</Location>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Kronosian</Location>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>Tethys</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Location>Vann</Location>
    <Location>Westley</Location>
    <Organization>HASR</Organization>
    <Organization>Hyper Acidic Substrate</Organization>
    <Organization>Karel</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
A Psycorps</Organization>
    <Organization>Stefano</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>Tiskele Bend.  He</Organization>
    <Organization>University of Abila</Organization>
    <Organization>Vann</Organization>
    <Person>Brief</Person>
    <Person>Di Stefano</Person>
    <Person>Elian</Person>
    <Person>Fredrick N. Wagner</Person>
    <Person>Isia Vann
Isia Vann</Person>
    <Person>Jakab</Person>
    <Person>Juliana Vann</Person>
    <Person>Karel.

Mandor</Person>
    <Person>Kronos</Person>
    <Person>Lucio Jakab
Lucio Jakab</Person>
    <Person>Mandor Vann</Person>
    <Person>Marek</Person>
    <Person>nephew to Mandor Vann.  Isia</Person>
    <Person>POK.

Lorenzo</Person>
    <Person>Silvia Marek
Marek</Person>
    <Person>Stefano
Lorenzo</Person>
    <Person>Vann</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Grassroots</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>The Application and Validation of a Social Movement Model in Understanding the Evolution and State of One Grassroots Social Movement in Kronos: Protectors of Kronos
A Thesis Presented for the Degree of Master of Humanities from the University of Abila, Kronos
October 2005
Kyrla Halford
Kyrla.halford@uabila.ac.kronos

This dissertation was submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the Degree of Master of Arts in Humanities at the University of Abila, Kronos, and the author is solely responsible for the content.

This project was sponsored in part by the One World Research Institute for Social Development and the Center for Change Now.

Case Study:  Protectors of Kronos, a History

Background

Elodis is a rural agricultural town of about 6500 persons that lies 25 km from Abila, capital city of Kronos.  The town was incorporated in 1834, but had already been settled for hundreds of years prior.  Its primary industry is floodplain farming, and is almost entirely dependent upon the nearby Tiskele River for irrigation and culinary water.  

The Issue:  Water Contamination

In early 1997 certain Elodis citizens convened a special town hall meeting to address their concerns about the increasing rate of illness and declining crop production the town had experienced over the last 18 months.  Armed with statistics form the Elodis Community Health Center, the citizens pointed toward an unusually high rate of cancer, neurological diseases, birth defects and respiratory illness.   They asked that the City Council approach the Kronos government to address the issues.  The specific source of the contamination was unclear, but several persons believed it had to be a result of the gas drilling operations several kilometers upstream.  This view was not universally embraced by the Elodis citizens at this point, but several persons agreed to explore the possibilities.

The City Council held several closed-door sessions and several public sessions to consider how to approach Kronos officials about the problem.    

Initial Stage:  Formation of the Grassroots Effort

When it became clear the Council could not agree on a course of action the Elodis citizens decided to address the problem independently.    At this point the SMO was in the initial stages of development, being still a group of citizens with similar concerns.  The primary actors in the initial stage formed the seven founding members of the Protectors of Kronos SMO:  Henk Bodrogi, Carmine Osvaldo, Ale L. Hanne, Jeroen Karel, Valentine Mies, Yanick Cato and Joreto Katell.  

Leaders

During the early stages of the effort Henk Bodrogi emerged as the leader.  While Bodrogi had no prior training in managing a social movement organization, he had served in the Kronos military as for four years before taking over the family farm when his father passed.  By 1997 Bodrogi was a well-respected member of the community, very experienced with floodplain agriculture techniques, and involved with civic business groups and considered a natural leader. Around this time, Bodrogi�s wife, Mira became ill with cardiopulmonary symptoms consistent with ethylene glycol contamination.

A lifelong friend of Bodrogi, Carmine Osvaldo also served with him in the Kronos military.  Osvaldo ran one of the hardware retail stores in Elodis and served on the board of the Chamber of Commerce.  Because of his business experience, Osvaldo became the primary navigator of the relationship between the burgeoning social movement, the Kronos government and outside agencies.

First Steps

The first steps of the group were to take the statistics assembled by the Elodis Community Health Center to the Abila office of the Minister of Interior, to request assistance to diagnose the problems associated with the Tiskele River.   Bodrogi presented the health statistics reports at several meetings, but was met with skepticism.  Feeling stymied, the group returned to Elodis to form a new approach.

In the meantime, Jeroen Karel and Valentine Mies had been conducting research and found a GAStech waste discharge pipe from the gas drilling operation was spilling raw waste into water that fed the Tiskele River, about 25 km upstream from Elodis.  They brought their discovery to Bodrogi, who had just returned with Osvaldo from their attempts at resolution in Abila.

Forming an Identity:  Protectors of Kronos

One of the critical steps for the formation of an SMO is to establish an identity that will help bring their message to the citizenry and the government.   Osvaldo proposed to the activists they form a social movement organization with an identity brand and a specific agenda:  To bring clean water to Elodis and clean up the contamination in the River.  The group formalized their identity with a name, the Protectors of Kronos (POK), and a logo, consisting of an open right hand within a white circle on a black background.

Osvaldo reached out to an international agency specializing in clear water for communities, Wellness for All (WFA).   The WFA Project Manager Joclyn Reynolds began formal scientific testing of the Tiskele River water, and advised the POK to engage the GAStech company regarding the issue of water contamination.  

Members of the POK repeatedly requested meetings with GAStech representatives, but received nothing but denials for several months.  This continued until Hank Fluss, the Chief Operating Officer at GAStech, agreed to a meeting with Bodrogi.  The meeting took place outside range of media, and involved only Fluss, Bodrogi and Osvaldo.  Bodrogi reported he felt encouraged by the seriousness with which Fluss took the POK agenda, and told the POK he would take their issues back to the CEO of GAStech, Sten Sanjorge, Jr.

Events Take a Turn for the Worse

Up to this point, the POK had primarily used statistics about health issues and names of toxins in their agenda, and then on August 18 1998 ten-year old Juliana Vann, daughter of Lemual and Neske Vann, died of leukemia associated with benzene toxicity.

This event also brought the first serious schism in the POK.  Valentine Mies suggested using her image as a rallying point, but Bodrogi and Yanick Cato were steadfastly against this approach.    After Mies negotiated approval from Juliana�s family, Bodrogi and Cato relented and the POK began using what would become an iconic image of Juliana smiling down over a daisy, tinted in Warhol-esque colors.  It was then that public awareness for POK across Kronos began rising.

The initial results from the WFA water testing in 1998 found high levels of chemicals associated with Hyper Acidic Substrate Removal, and technology associated with natural gas drilling operations.  Several toxic substances were found Elodis water, including benzene, toluene and xylene arsenic, barium, chromium, lead and selenium.  WFA published these results in international health organization conferences, bringing increasingly widespread awareness of the Elodisan situation.

Membership Numbers Increase

Following the death of Juliana and the publication of the scientific reports, the number of persons interested in joining the POK efforts increased.  Up to this point most of the work had been done by the founding members and their extended families; however increased media awareness brought additional interest.  Jeroen Karel stepped into the role as recruiter and personnel organizer.

Alliance Stage:  Operations move to Abila

With the establishment of their agenda and international acknowledgement of their issue, the Protectors of Kronos are recognized as a formal SMO, and moved their primary lobbying efforts to the capital city of Kronos.  They stage a series of public rallies, and continued their efforts to press the government for action.  With public pressure mounting, the office of the Minister of Health responded by agreeing to a series of meetings.   By July 1999 Cesare Nespola, Minister of Health, announced he would sponsor a  bill on oil and gas development, the funds of which would be used for health care and clean water projects.

While they appear to have had public support, the POK continued to find most doors closed to them.  The only traction the POK appeared to make is with the Minister of Health.   Negotiations with GAStech via Hank Fluss didn�t continue due to Fluss� declining health. 

The POK continued to press the Kronos government; however it became increasingly clear their every effort would be blocked. 

In March 2001 the Government of Kronos Assembly voted down the tax proposed by Minister Nespola, and in June 2001 Minister Nespola died suddenly.  With Nespola�s death, the POK lost the only government official who was willing to engage with them.

When an underground methane deposit ignited at the GAStech mining operations near Elodis in August 2001, POK demanded an investigation of GAStech by the Kronos government.   In response, the POK staged a protest at the GAStech fields.  This protest marked the first time POK supporters were arrested. One protester threw a sign at a government vehicle, which precipitated the arrests.  POK member Elian Karel, 20-year old son of Jeroen, was present at the August protest.  He entreated the POK to disengage with the drivers and deescalate the situation by withdrawing from the road.  The POK members retreated, allowing the drivers to move along, and Karel was heralded as a hero for preventing further violence.

Changing of the Guard

It was at this point that Henk Bodrogi and the other original POK members began considering they might not be able to keep up the pace required to maintain pressure on the government.  All the men were in late middle age, and many were suffering health problems so common to the Elodisians. 

Elian Karel had been involved with the POK, assisting his father with recruitment and organizing rallies.  Following the August 2001 incident, Henk began taking Karel to rallies and turning over public appearance responsibilities to Karel.   In October 2001 Henk Bodrogi stepped down as leader of the POK, formally handing his responsibilities to Elian Karel.  The remaining founding members would follow by the end of that year.

Karel reinvigorated the POK mission.  But he began shifting the agenda to include an additional issue.

It had become clear through the lack of government response to POK requests and the protection the government offered GAStech following malfeasance that an unusual and potentially illegal alliance had been formed between the GAStech executives and the Kronos government officials.  The POK shifted their mission to include an accounting of actions by government officials.  The public concern about bribes and corruption would change the direction of the Protectors of Kronos, and bring many more supporters into their fold.</docText>
    <Location>Abila</Location>
    <Location>Elodis</Location>
    <Location>Fluss</Location>
    <Location>GAStech</Location>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Kronos
A</Location>
    <Location>Kronos.</Location>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>the Kronos</Location>
    <Location>the River</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Location>town</Location>
    <Location>Warhol</Location>
    <Organization>Abila</Organization>
    <Organization>Bodrogi</Organization>
    <Organization>Bodrogi and Cato</Organization>
    <Organization>Chamber of Commerce.</Organization>
    <Organization>Elodis Community Health Center</Organization>
    <Organization>Fluss</Organization>
    <Organization>GAStech</Organization>
    <Organization>Hank Fluss</Organization>
    <Organization>Hyper Acidic Substrate</Organization>
    <Organization>Jr</Organization>
    <Organization>Juliana</Organization>
    <Organization>Karel.</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos SMO</Organization>
    <Organization>Lemual</Organization>
    <Organization>Master of Humanities</Organization>
    <Organization>Minister of Health</Organization>
    <Organization>One World Research Institute for Social Development</Organization>
    <Organization>Osvaldo</Organization>
    <Organization>POK mission</Organization>
    <Organization>POK.  Valentine Mies</Organization>
    <Organization>Reynolds</Organization>
    <Organization>SMO</Organization>
    <Organization>the Center for Change Now.

Case Study:  Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors of Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>Tiskele River.</Organization>
    <Organization>uabila.ac.</Organization>
    <Organization>University of Abila</Organization>
    <Organization>Valentine Mies</Organization>
    <Organization>Water Contamination</Organization>
    <Organization>Wellness</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA Project</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA).</Organization>
    <Organization>Yanick</Organization>
    <Person>Ale L. Hanne</Person>
    <Person>Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Carmine Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Elian Karel</Person>
    <Person>Elodis</Person>
    <Person>ethylene glycol</Person>
    <Person>Feeling</Person>
    <Person>Halford
Kyrla.halford</Person>
    <Person>Hank Fluss</Person>
    <Person>Henk Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Jeroen</Person>
    <Person>Jeroen Karel</Person>
    <Person>Joreto Katell</Person>
    <Person>Juliana Vann</Person>
    <Person>Juliana�s</Person>
    <Person>Karel</Person>
    <Person>Neske Vann</Person>
    <Person>Nespola</Person>
    <Person>Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Osvaldo.  Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Sten Sanjorge</Person>
    <Person>While Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>With Nespola</Person>
    <Person>xylene arsenic</Person>
    <Person>Yanick Cato</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Futures</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>History of the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps Analysis Brief
By Fredrick N. Wagner and Westley B. Andrews
January 2009

Three Possible Futures (2009 and forward)
Social movements go through stages of growth and change, in some cases growing systematically in strength and impact over time and in others fluctuating in response to internal dynamics and external pressures.  To accomplish its goals, a social movement needs to win over the neutrality, sympathies, opinions, and even support of an increasingly larger majority of the populace and involve many of them in the process of opposition and change. The central agency of opposition must slowly change from the new wave activists and groups to the great majority of nonpolitical populace and the mainstream political forces as they are convinced to agree with the movement's position. The majority stage is a long process of eroding the social, political, and economic supports that enable the powerholders to continue their policies. 
Movements can also cease to exist, most commonly when a movement�s central cause has been addressed.  Movements may also end due to internal factors such as failure to adapt political agendas to changing contexts or concerns of members, or internal conflicts over politics and power.  Other reasons for movements to cease include systematic suppression by external forces that dissipate actors and make action impossible.  This can include targeted harassment and killing of key activists, and campaigns to discredit visible leaders.  While repression can suppress a social movement, it may make militancy more likely if it suppresses moderate alternatives, radicalizes remaining supporters, and creates martyrs and myths that militants use to justify their actions.
In the context of the lifecycle of a social movement, the authors see three possible futures for the POK: dissolution, consolidation into a political entity, or radicalization.  The most likely future is the one in which the POK, like so many other social movements before it, dissolves before it can achieve its goals.

Dissolution of the POK 
Those who joined the POK when it was growing expect rapid success. If this is not realized, members experience feelings of hopelessness and burn-out and will leave the organization.  This future is the most likely, especially if Elian Karel or others of the dominant POK personalities fail to make progress in engaging the Kronosian government or become disillusioned and leave the group.  Dissolution is also likely if the Kronosian government suppresses the POK�s ability to act, leaving the membership feeling powerless and ineffective. 

The POK as a Political Entity
The POK, under the leadership of its popular leader Elian Karel, could become a powerful political entity.  This future can be achieved if Karel is successful in consolidating the POK membership, formalizing a leadership structure and popularize their agenda.  Karel will need to build a broad-based pluralized movement, conduct massive public education and conversion, renew the use of mainstream political and social institutions, and develop programs in which large numbers of common citizens can become actively involved in programs that challenge current traditions, policies, and laws.

Radicalization of the POK
A large number of the POK members recruited since 2001 are under-employed and under-educated young males who feel as if they have no future since their country is changing from an agrarian-based economy to an energy-based economy in which they are unable to compete against outsiders for high paying jobs.  Elian Karel has so far been able to control these members and channel their energy towards political protest.  Should Karel leave the POK, leadership of the group would probably fall to either Silvia Marek or Mandor Vann (see personality profiles below).  These young disaffected members of the POK would likely prove a challenge for Marek�s leadership skills and many may break ranks from her program of peaceful engagement.  Mandor Vann�s military background makes him more likely to be able to restrain the actions of the disaffected young male members of the POK than Marek, but his ties to Isia and Juliana Vann may make him more sympathetic to a course of more radical action to promote the POK agenda.  In either case there exists a possibility of radicalization within the POK ranks.</docText>
    <Location>Isia</Location>
    <Location>Kronosian</Location>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>Westley</Location>
    <Organization>Karel</Organization>
    <Organization>Marek</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps</Organization>
    <Person>Elian Karel</Person>
    <Person>Fredrick N. Wagner</Person>
    <Person>Juliana Vann</Person>
    <Person>Karel</Person>
    <Person>Mandor Vann</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Case Study</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>The Application and Validation of a Social Movement Model in Understanding the Evolution and State of One Grassroots Social Movement in Kronos: Protectors of Kronos
A Thesis Presented for the Degree of Master of Humanities from the University of Abila, Kronos
October 2005
Kyrla Halford
Kyrla.halford@uabila.ac.kronos

This dissertation was submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the Degree of Master of Arts in Humanities at the University of Abila, Kronos, and the author is solely responsible for the content.

This project was sponsored in part by the One World Research Institute for Social Development and the Center for Change Now.

Case Study:  Protectors of Kronos, a History

Background

Elodis is a rural agricultural town of about 6500 persons that lies 25 km from Abila, capital city of Kronos.  The town was incorporated in 1834, but had already been settled for hundreds of years prior.  Its primary industry is floodplain farming, and is almost entirely dependent upon the nearby Tiskele River for irrigation and culinary water.  

The Issue:  Water Contamination

In early 1997 certain Elodis citizens convened a special town hall meeting to address their concerns about the increasing rate of illness and declining crop production the town had experienced over the last 18 months.  Armed with statistics form the Elodis Community Health Center, the citizens pointed toward an unusually high rate of cancer, neurological diseases, birth defects and respiratory illness.   They asked that the City Council approach the Kronos government to address the issues.  The specific source of the contamination was unclear, but several persons believed it had to be a result of the gas drilling operations several kilometers upstream.  This view was not universally embraced by the Elodis citizens at this point, but several persons agreed to explore the possibilities.

The City Council held several closed-door sessions and several public sessions to consider how to approach Kronos officials about the problem.    

Initial Stage:  Formation of the Grassroots Effort

When it became clear the Council could not agree on a course of action the Elodis citizens decided to address the problem independently.    At this point the SMO was in the initial stages of development, being still a group of citizens with similar concerns.  The primary actors in the initial stage formed the seven founding members of the Protectors of Kronos SMO:  Henk Bodrogi, Carmine Osvaldo, Ale L. Hanne, Jeroen Karel, Valentine Mies, Yanick Cato and Joreto Katell.  

Leaders

During the early stages of the effort Henk Bodrogi emerged as the leader.  While Bodrogi had no prior training in managing a social movement organization, he had served in the Kronos military as for four years before taking over the family farm when his father passed.  By 1997 Bodrogi was a well-respected member of the community, very experienced with floodplain agriculture techniques, and involved with civic business groups and considered a natural leader. Around this time, Bodrogi�s wife, Mira became ill with cardiopulmonary symptoms consistent with ethylene glycol contamination.

A lifelong friend of Bodrogi, Carmine Osvaldo also served with him in the Kronos military.  Osvaldo ran one of the hardware retail stores in Elodis and served on the board of the Chamber of Commerce.  Because of his business experience, Osvaldo became the primary navigator of the relationship between the burgeoning social movement, the Kronos government and outside agencies.

First Steps

The first steps of the group were to take the statistics assembled by the Elodis Community Health Center to the Abila office of the Minister of Interior, to request assistance to diagnose the problems associated with the Tiskele River.   Bodrogi presented the health statistics reports at several meetings, but was met with skepticism.  Feeling stymied, the group returned to Elodis to form a new approach.

In the meantime, Jeroen Karel and Valentine Mies had been conducting research and found a GAStech waste discharge pipe from the gas drilling operation was spilling raw waste into water that fed the Tiskele River, about 25 km upstream from Elodis.  They brought their discovery to Bodrogi, who had just returned with Osvaldo from their attempts at resolution in Abila.

Forming an Identity:  Protectors of Kronos

One of the critical steps for the formation of an SMO is to establish an identity that will help bring their message to the citizenry and the government.   Osvaldo proposed to the activists they form a social movement organization with an identity brand and a specific agenda:  To bring clean water to Elodis and clean up the contamination in the River.  The group formalized their identity with a name, the Protectors of Kronos (POK), and a logo, consisting of an open right hand within a white circle on a black background.

Osvaldo reached out to an international agency specializing in clear water for communities, Wellness for All (WFA).   The WFA Project Manager Joclyn Reynolds began formal scientific testing of the Tiskele River water, and advised the POK to engage the GAStech company regarding the issue of water contamination.  

Members of the POK repeatedly requested meetings with GAStech representatives, but received nothing but denials for several months.  This continued until Hank Fluss, the Chief Operating Officer at GAStech, agreed to a meeting with Bodrogi.  The meeting took place outside range of media, and involved only Fluss, Bodrogi and Osvaldo.  Bodrogi reported he felt encouraged by the seriousness with which Fluss took the POK agenda, and told the POK he would take their issues back to the CEO of GAStech, Sten Sanjorge, Jr.

Events Take a Turn for the Worse

Up to this point, the POK had primarily used statistics about health issues and names of toxins in their agenda, and then on August 18 1998 ten-year old Juliana Vann, daughter of Lemual and Neske Vann, died of leukemia associated with benzene toxicity.

This event also brought the first serious schism in the POK.  Valentine Mies suggested using her image as a rallying point, but Bodrogi and Yanick Cato were steadfastly against this approach.    After Mies negotiated approval from Juliana�s family, Bodrogi and Cato relented and the POK began using what would become an iconic image of Juliana smiling down over a daisy, tinted in Warhol-esque colors.  It was then that public awareness for POK across Kronos began rising.

The initial results from the WFA water testing in 1998 found high levels of chemicals associated with Hyper Acidic Substrate Removal, and technology associated with natural gas drilling operations.  Several toxic substances were found Elodis water, including benzene, toluene and xylene arsenic, barium, chromium, lead and selenium.  WFA published these results in international health organization conferences, bringing increasingly widespread awareness of the Elodisan situation.

Membership Numbers Increase

Following the death of Juliana and the publication of the scientific reports, the number of persons interested in joining the POK efforts increased.  Up to this point most of the work had been done by the founding members and their extended families; however increased media awareness brought additional interest.  Jeroen Karel stepped into the role as recruiter and personnel organizer.

Alliance Stage:  Operations move to Abila

With the establishment of their agenda and international acknowledgement of their issue, the Protectors of Kronos are recognized as a formal SMO, and moved their primary lobbying efforts to the capital city of Kronos.  They stage a series of public rallies, and continued their efforts to press the government for action.  With public pressure mounting, the office of the Minister of Health responded by agreeing to a series of meetings.   By July 1999 Cesare Nespola, Minister of Health, announced he would sponsor a  bill on oil and gas development, the funds of which would be used for health care and clean water projects.

While they appear to have had public support, the POK continued to find most doors closed to them.  The only traction the POK appeared to make is with the Minister of Health.   Negotiations with GAStech via Hank Fluss didn�t continue due to Fluss� declining health. 

The POK continued to press the Kronos government; however it became increasingly clear their every effort would be blocked. 

In March 2001 the Government of Kronos Assembly voted down the tax proposed by Minister Nespola, and in June 2001 Minister Nespola died suddenly.  With Nespola�s death, the POK lost the only government official who was willing to engage with them.

When an underground methane deposit ignited at the GAStech mining operations near Elodis in August 2001, POK demanded an investigation of GAStech by the Kronos government.   In response, the POK staged a protest at the GAStech fields.  This protest marked the first time POK supporters were arrested. One protester threw a sign at a government vehicle, which precipitated the arrests.  POK member Elian Karel, 20-year old son of Jeroen, was present at the August protest.  He entreated the POK to disengage with the drivers and deescalate the situation by withdrawing from the road.  The POK members retreated, allowing the drivers to move along, and Karel was heralded as a hero for preventing further violence.

Changing of the Guard

It was at this point that Henk Bodrogi and the other original POK members began considering they might not be able to keep up the pace required to maintain pressure on the government.  All the men were in late middle age, and many were suffering health problems so common to the Elodisians. 

Elian Karel had been involved with the POK, assisting his father with recruitment and organizing rallies.  Following the August 2001 incident, Henk began taking Karel to rallies and turning over public appearance responsibilities to Karel.   In October 2001 Henk Bodrogi stepped down as leader of the POK, formally handing his responsibilities to Elian Karel.  The remaining founding members would follow by the end of that year.

Karel reinvigorated the POK mission.  But he began shifting the agenda to include an additional issue.

It had become clear through the lack of government response to POK requests and the protection the government offered GAStech following malfeasance that an unusual and potentially illegal alliance had been formed between the GAStech executives and the Kronos government officials.  The POK shifted their mission to include an accounting of actions by government officials.  The public concern about bribes and corruption would change the direction of the Protectors of Kronos, and bring many more supporters into their fold.</docText>
    <Location>Abila</Location>
    <Location>Elodis</Location>
    <Location>Fluss</Location>
    <Location>GAStech</Location>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Kronos
A</Location>
    <Location>Kronos.</Location>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>the Kronos</Location>
    <Location>the River</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Location>town</Location>
    <Location>Warhol</Location>
    <Organization>Abila</Organization>
    <Organization>Bodrogi</Organization>
    <Organization>Bodrogi and Cato</Organization>
    <Organization>Chamber of Commerce.</Organization>
    <Organization>Elodis Community Health Center</Organization>
    <Organization>Fluss</Organization>
    <Organization>GAStech</Organization>
    <Organization>Hank Fluss</Organization>
    <Organization>Hyper Acidic Substrate</Organization>
    <Organization>Jr</Organization>
    <Organization>Juliana</Organization>
    <Organization>Karel.</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos SMO</Organization>
    <Organization>Lemual</Organization>
    <Organization>Master of Humanities</Organization>
    <Organization>Minister of Health</Organization>
    <Organization>One World Research Institute for Social Development</Organization>
    <Organization>Osvaldo</Organization>
    <Organization>POK mission</Organization>
    <Organization>POK.  Valentine Mies</Organization>
    <Organization>Reynolds</Organization>
    <Organization>SMO</Organization>
    <Organization>the Center for Change Now.

Case Study:  Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors of Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>Tiskele River.</Organization>
    <Organization>uabila.ac.</Organization>
    <Organization>University of Abila</Organization>
    <Organization>Valentine Mies</Organization>
    <Organization>Water Contamination</Organization>
    <Organization>Wellness</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA Project</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA).</Organization>
    <Organization>Yanick</Organization>
    <Person>Ale L. Hanne</Person>
    <Person>Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Carmine Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Elian Karel</Person>
    <Person>Elodis</Person>
    <Person>ethylene glycol</Person>
    <Person>Feeling</Person>
    <Person>Halford
Kyrla.halford</Person>
    <Person>Hank Fluss</Person>
    <Person>Henk Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Jeroen</Person>
    <Person>Jeroen Karel</Person>
    <Person>Joreto Katell</Person>
    <Person>Juliana Vann</Person>
    <Person>Juliana�s</Person>
    <Person>Karel</Person>
    <Person>Neske Vann</Person>
    <Person>Nespola</Person>
    <Person>Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Osvaldo.  Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Sten Sanjorge</Person>
    <Person>While Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>With Nespola</Person>
    <Person>xylene arsenic</Person>
    <Person>Yanick Cato</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Activism and Protest</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>History of the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps Analysis Brief
By Fredrick N. Wagner and Westley B. Andrews
January 2009

Activism and Protest (2005-2008)
Karel continued the group�s mission of peaceful protest in order to seek government action on the contamination of the Tiskele River, but the tone of the POK protests changed markedly after the Tiskele River caught fire in 2005.  At their recent rallies, the POK has alleged that government corruption and possible collusion has resulted in little to no oversight of gas and oil field operations.  POK rallies have also been marked by an increase in civil disobedience and militant, violent action.  It is unclear if this represents a change in tactics by Karel, or if it is evidence that he has lost some measure of control over the more radical members of his group.</docText>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Location>Westley</Location>
    <Organization>the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps</Organization>
    <Person>Fredrick N. Wagner</Person>
    <Person>Karel</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Acknowledgments</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>The Application and Validation of a Social Movement Model in Understanding the Evolution and State of One Grassroots Social Movement in Kronos: Protectors of Kronos
A Thesis Presented for the Degree of Master of Humanities from the University of Abila, Kronos
October 2005
Kyrla Halford
Kyrla.halford@uabila.ac.kronos

This dissertation was submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the Degree of Master of Arts in Humanities at the University of Abila, Kronos, and the author is solely responsible for the content.

This project was sponsored in part by the One World Research Institute for Social Development and the Center for Change Now.

ACKNOWLEDGMENTS

Special thanks go to my advisor, Esme Nesmith, without whose encouragement and guidance this thesis would not have been completed.
I am especially grateful to Elian Karel, who spent many hours recounting the beginning years of the Protectors of Kronos. 
I would also like to express my sincere gratitude to the people of Elodis who generously gave of their time to meet with me.
Finally, I would like to extend special appreciation to Petrus Gerhard who shared his interview notes on his coverage of the inception and early years of the Protectors of Kronos movement.


This thesis is dedicated to the memory of Juliana Vann, a beloved girl who left this life too early.  Her courage in the face of suffering sets an example for us all.</docText>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Kronos.</Location>
    <Organization>Elodis</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
A Thesis</Organization>
    <Organization>Master of Humanities</Organization>
    <Organization>One World Research Institute for Social Development</Organization>
    <Organization>the Center for Change Now.

ACKNOWLEDGMENTS

I</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors of Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>uabila.ac.</Organization>
    <Organization>University of Abila</Organization>
    <Person>Elian Karel</Person>
    <Person>Esme Nesmith</Person>
    <Person>Halford
Kyrla.halford</Person>
    <Person>Juliana Vann</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>POK Abstract</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>The Application and Validation of a Social Movement Model in Understanding the Evolution and State of One Grassroots Social Movement in Kronos: Protectors of Kronos
A Thesis Presented for the Degree of Master of Humanities from the University of Abila, Kronos
October 2005
Kyrla Halford
Kyrla.halford@uabila.ac.kronos

This dissertation was submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the Degree of Master of Arts in Humanities at the University of Abila, Kronos, and the author is solely responsible for the content.

This project was sponsored in part by the One World Research Institute for Social Development and the Center for Change Now.

Abstract

In 1997 a group of citizens from Elodis, Kronos, formed a grassroots effort to address a problem of contamination of their irrigation, culinary and potable water supply affecting the nearby Tiskele River.  The formation of this movement and its transformation into a formal social movement organization (SMO) is the topic of this thesis.</docText>
    <Location>Elodis</Location>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Organization>Kronos
A Thesis</Organization>
    <Organization>Master of Humanities</Organization>
    <Organization>One World Research Institute for Social Development</Organization>
    <Organization>SMO</Organization>
    <Organization>the Center for Change Now.</Organization>
    <Organization>the University of Abila</Organization>
    <Organization>uabila.ac.</Organization>
    <Organization>University of Abila</Organization>
    <Person>Halford
Kyrla.halford</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>Kronos_Intro</docID>
    <docDate></docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>History of the Protectors of Kronos
A Psycorps Analysis Brief
By Fredrick N. Wagner and Westley B. Andrews
January 2009

The protectors of Kronos emerged from the Elodis township, a rural agricultural town of about 6500 persons that lies 25 km from Abila, capital city of Kronos.  The people of Elodis are primarily engaged in floodplain farming which is dependent upon the Tiskele River for irrigation.  In early 1997, citizens of Elodis began to be concerned about an abnormal increase in the occurrence of illnesses such as cancer, birth defects, respiratory illnesses, and neurological diseases, in addition to a marked decrease in crop yield.  When the Elodis City Council failed to take action on the citizen�s call for investigation into possible contamination of the river, a small grassroots group of seven citizens formed with the goal of bringing their concerns to the central Kronos government.  
The grassroots organization coalesced under the leadership of Henk Bodrogi, a floodplain farmer who had joined the group after his wife had become ill with cardiopulmonary symptoms consistent with ethylene glycol contamination.  Bodrogi was a popular local figure who was well regarded for his leadership in civic groups.  Although he had served in the Kronosian military, Bodrogi lacked experience in dealing with the Kronosian government and for which he turned to his lifelong friend, Carmine Osvaldo. Osvaldo, who had served in the military with Bodrogi, was a member of the board for the Elodis Chamber of Commerce and who used his business experience to form relationships with the Kronosian government and outside agencies.
Osvaldo proposed to the activists that they form a social movement organization with an identity brand and a specific agenda as a mechanism for interfacing with the government of Kronos.  The group chose the name �Protectors of Kronos� and developed a logo consisting of an open right hand rising from the land on a black background.  Additionally, Osvaldo contacted Wellness for All (WFA), an international agency that specialized in providing clean water for rural communities.  WFA tested water from the Tiskele River both upstream and downstream of the Tiskele Bend gas fields and confirmed the presence of contaminants consistent with pollution from Hyper Acidic Substrate Removal, a gas drilling technique employed by GAStech at the Tiskele Bend fields.  The WFA published these test results in several international journals, which gathered attention in the media and brought new members to the POK. With the increase in POK membership, Bodrogi and Osvaldo turned to Jeroen Karel, father of current POK leader Elian Karel, to organize recruitment and personnel.  
Armed with the WFA test results, Bodrogi and Osvaldo sought to meet with GAStech to discuss the contamination issue, and after much persistence, were able to meet with Hank Fluss, GAStech�s Chief Operating Officer.  Fluss assured the men that he would discuss the contamination issue with GAStech CEO Sten Sanjorge, Jr., but there is no evidence that Sanjorge made any changes to his company�s operations at the Tiskele Bend fields.
The publicity garnered from the WFA test results convinced Osvaldo to step up the POK�s lobbying efforts in the capital city of Abila.  After numerous meetings with low-level government functionaries and many peaceful rallies in front of the capitol, Bodrogi and Osvaldo were invited to attend several meetings with the Minister of Health, Cesare Nespola.  Nespola investigated the POK claims and eventually grew concerned enough that in July 1999 he sponsored a bill to create an additional tax on oil and gas development, the funds from which would be specifically earmarked for health care and clean water projects in rural areas.  The tax measure was defeated in March 2001, and Nespola died soon after.  Nespola�s successor, Vincent Kapelou, the 28-year-old nephew of President Kapelou, was less sympathetic to the POK�s plight and refused to re-introduce the tax measure to the General Assembly.
With this setback to the POK�s efforts to engage the government in addressing the contamination of the Tiskele River, the group turned to protesting at the entrance to the government-controlled Tiskele Bend fields in August 2001 in order to refocus attention on their cause.  The protest was successful, and became the first of many POK public protests.
Following the August protest, Henk Bodrogi, who was suffering from health problems related to the Tiskele River contamination, decided to step down as leader of the POK.  Bodrogi chose Elian Karel, a young charismatic man, as his replacement.  Within one month of Henk�s departure from the POK, all of the other original seven members of the group also quit and returned home to Elodis.</docText>
    <Location>Abila</Location>
    <Location>central Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Jr.</Location>
    <Location>Kronos</Location>
    <Location>Kronosian</Location>
    <Location>Kronos�</Location>
    <Location>Osvaldo</Location>
    <Location>POK</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele</Location>
    <Location>Tiskele River</Location>
    <Location>Westley</Location>
    <Organization>Cesare Nespola.  Nespola</Organization>
    <Organization>Elodis</Organization>
    <Organization>Elodis Chamber of Commerce</Organization>
    <Organization>Elodis City Council</Organization>
    <Organization>fields.</Organization>
    <Organization>GAStech</Organization>
    <Organization>Henk�</Organization>
    <Organization>Hyper Acidic Substrate</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
A Psycorps</Organization>
    <Organization>Minister of Health</Organization>
    <Organization>Osvaldo</Organization>
    <Organization>Sanjorge</Organization>
    <Organization>the Protectors</Organization>
    <Organization>Tiskele</Organization>
    <Organization>Tiskele Bend</Organization>
    <Organization>WFA</Organization>
    <Person>Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Brief</Person>
    <Person>Carmine Osvaldo. Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Elian Karel</Person>
    <Person>Elodis</Person>
    <Person>ethylene glycol</Person>
    <Person>Fredrick N. Wagner</Person>
    <Person>Hank Fluss</Person>
    <Person>Henk Bodrogi</Person>
    <Person>Jeroen Karel</Person>
    <Person>Kapelou</Person>
    <Person>Nespola</Person>
    <Person>Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Sten Sanjorge</Person>
    <Person>WFA</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_9</docID>
    <docDate>10/22/79</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Borrasca
FirstName: Isande
BirthDate: 10/22/79
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 10/22/79
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 10/3/08
PassportExpiration: 10/2/18
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Drill Technician
EmploymentStart: 2/18/04
email: Isande.Borrasca@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Borrasca
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Drill Technician
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Isande
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Isande.Borrasca</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_8</docID>
    <docDate>4/17/89</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Bodrogi
FirstName: Loreto
BirthDate: 4/17/89
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 4/17/89
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Site Control
EmploymentStart: 8/17/13
email: Loreto.Bodrogi@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/08</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security</Organization>
    <Organization>Site Control
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>Bodrogi
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Loreto
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Loreto.Bodrogi</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_7</docID>
    <docDate>7/10/69</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Bergen
FirstName: Linnea
BirthDate: 7/10/69
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 7/10/69
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 4/29/04
PassportExpiration: 4/28/14
CurrentEmployment: Information Technology
CurrentTitle: IT Group Manager
EmploymentStart: 7/4/04
email: Linnea.Bergen@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Information Technology</Organization>
    <Organization>IT Group Manager
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Bergen
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Linnea
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Linnea.Bergen</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_6</docID>
    <docDate>2/12/79</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Baza
FirstName: Isak
BirthDate: 2/12/79
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 2/12/79
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 8/13/08
PassportExpiration: 8/12/18
CurrentEmployment: Information Technology
CurrentTitle: IT Technician
EmploymentStart: 3/20/02
email: Isak.Baza@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Information Technology</Organization>
    <Organization>Isak.Baza</Organization>
    <Organization>IT Technician
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Baza
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Isak
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_53</docID>
    <docDate>3/18/75</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Vasco-Pais
FirstName: Willem
BirthDate: 3/18/75
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 3/18/75
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 11/26/11
PassportExpiration: 11/25/21
CurrentEmployment: Executive
CurrentTitle: Environmental Safety Advisor
EmploymentStart: 6/5/10
email: Willem.Vasco-Pais@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>BirthCountry</Location>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Location>Pais</Location>
    <Location>Willem.Vasco</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Environmental Safety Advisor
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Organization>Vasco-Pais
FirstName</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Willem
BirthDate</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_52</docID>
    <docDate>3/18/91</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Vann
FirstName: Edvard
BirthDate: 3/18/91
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 3/18/91
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart: 8/15/13
email: Edvard.Vann@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/11</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security</Organization>
    <Organization>Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Vann
FirstName</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>Edvard
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Edvard.Vann</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_51</docID>
    <docDate>12/13/86</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Vann
FirstName: Isia
BirthDate: 12/13/86
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 12/13/86
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart: 12/14/07
email: Isia.Vann@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/07</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Isia
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security</Organization>
    <Organization>Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Vann
FirstName</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Isia.Vann</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_50</docID>
    <docDate>5/14/79</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Tempestad
FirstName: Brand
BirthDate: 5/14/79
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 5/14/79
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 5/5/12
PassportExpiration: 5/4/22
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Drill Technician
EmploymentStart: 6/12/04
email: Brand.Tempestad@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Brand.Tempestad</Organization>
    <Organization>Drill Technician
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tempestad
FirstName: Brand</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_5</docID>
    <docDate>10/26/61</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Barranco
FirstName: Ingrid
BirthDate: 10/26/61
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 10/26/61
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 7/1/13
PassportExpiration: 6/30/23
CurrentEmployment: Executive
CurrentTitle: SVP/CFO
EmploymentStart: 9/30/03
email: Ingrid.Barranco@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Ingrid
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>Ingrid.Barranco</Organization>
    <Organization>SVP/CFO
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>LastName: Barranco
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_49</docID>
    <docDate>10/18/63</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Strum
FirstName: Orhan
BirthDate: 10/18/63
BirthCountry: Asteria
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: ParentCitizenship
CitizenStart: 10/18/63
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 6/2/11
PassportExpiration: 6/1/21
CurrentEmployment: Executive
CurrentTitle: SVP/COO
EmploymentStart: 8/7/03
email: Orhan.Strum@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>Strum
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>SVP/COO
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Asteria
Gender</Person>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Orhan
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Orhan.Strum</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_48</docID>
    <docDate>5/25/86</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Scozzese
FirstName: Dylan
BirthDate: 5/25/86
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 5/25/86
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 3/1/07
email: Dylan.Scozzese@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/06</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Dylan
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities</Organization>
    <Organization>Truck Driver
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>Dylan.Scozzese</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Scozzese
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_47</docID>
    <docDate>8/29/48</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Sanjorge Jr.
FirstName: Sten
BirthDate: 8/29/48
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 8/29/48
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 4/21/13
PassportExpiration: 4/20/23
CurrentEmployment: Executive
CurrentTitle: President/CEO
EmploymentStart: 11/9/90
email: Sten.Sanjorge Jr.@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthCountry</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Sanjorge Jr.
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>Sten
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Sten.Sanjorge Jr.</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_46</docID>
    <docDate>11/17/75</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Ribera
FirstName: Anda
BirthDate: 11/17/75
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 11/17/75
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 6/15/09
PassportExpiration: 6/14/19
CurrentEmployment: Administration
CurrentTitle: Assistant to CFO
EmploymentStart: 10/30/09
email: Anda.Ribera@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>BirthCountry</Location>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>Administration</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>CFO
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Anda
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Anda.Ribera</Person>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Ribera
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_45</docID>
    <docDate>6/30/59</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Resumir
FirstName: Felix
BirthDate: 6/30/59
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 6/30/59
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 3/20/05
PassportExpiration: 3/19/15
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Security Group Manager
EmploymentStart: 9/15/03
email: Felix.Resumir@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: TethanDefenseForceArmy
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/97</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Felix
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>Resumir
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Security
CurrentTitle</Organization>
    <Organization>Security Group Manager
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>TethanDefenseForceArmy
DischargeType</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Felix.Resumir</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_44</docID>
    <docDate>8/22/84</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Pantanal
FirstName: Rachel
BirthDate: 8/22/84
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 8/22/84
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 6/13/13
PassportExpiration: 6/12/23
CurrentEmployment: Administration
CurrentTitle: Assistant to CIO
EmploymentStart: 10/1/13
email: Rachel.Pantanal@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>Administration</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>CIO
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Pantanal
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Rachel
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>Rachel.Pantanal</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_43</docID>
    <docDate>12/12/64</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Ovan
FirstName: Bertrand
BirthDate: 12/12/64
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 12/12/64
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 10/3/08
PassportExpiration: 10/2/18
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Facilities Group Manager
EmploymentStart: 10/1/98
email: Bertrand.Ovan@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: TethanDefenseForceAir
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/93</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Facilities Group Manager
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Ovan
FirstName: Bertrand
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>TethanDefenseForceAir</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Bertrand.Ovan</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_42</docID>
    <docDate>5/31/88</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Osvaldo
FirstName: Hennie
BirthDate: 5/31/88
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 5/31/88
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart: 6/7/11
email: Hennie.Osvaldo@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/10</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security</Organization>
    <Organization>Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Hennie
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Hennie.Osvaldo</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Osvaldo
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_41</docID>
    <docDate>2/29/64</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Orilla
FirstName: Kare
BirthDate: 2/29/64
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 2/29/64
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 7/1/13
PassportExpiration: 6/30/23
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Drill Technician
EmploymentStart: 11/12/05
email: Kare.Orilla@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Drill Technician
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Orilla
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kare
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Kare.Orilla</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_40</docID>
    <docDate>4/12/82</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Orilla
FirstName: Elsa
BirthDate: 4/12/82
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 4/12/82
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 2/28/10
PassportExpiration: 2/27/20
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Drill Technician
EmploymentStart: 5/26/04
email: Elsa.Orilla@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Drill Technician
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Elsa
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>Elsa.Orilla</Organization>
    <Organization>Orilla
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_4</docID>
    <docDate>3/4/60</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Balas
FirstName: Felix
BirthDate: 3/4/60
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 3/4/60
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 4/15/05
PassportExpiration: 4/14/15
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Engineer
EmploymentStart: 9/2/04
email: Felix.Balas@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: TethanDefenseForceNavy
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/88</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Engineer
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Felix
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>TethanDefenseForceNavy</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Balas
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>Felix.Balas</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_39</docID>
    <docDate>12/31/69</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Onda
FirstName: Marin
BirthDate: 12/31/69
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 12/31/69
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 4/15/05
PassportExpiration: 4/14/15
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Drill Site Manager
EmploymentStart: 4/13/03
email: Marin.Onda@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Drill Site Manager
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Onda
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Marin
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Marin.Onda</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_38</docID>
    <docDate>6/6/68</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Nubarron
FirstName: Adra
BirthDate: 6/6/68
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 6/6/68
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 11/12/07
PassportExpiration: 11/11/17
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Geologist
EmploymentStart: 7/8/94
email: Adra.Nubarron@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>Adra
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Geologist
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Nubarron
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Adra.Nubarron</Person>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_37</docID>
    <docDate>3/13/85</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Nant
FirstName: Irene
BirthDate: 3/13/85
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 3/13/85
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 11/30/08
email: Irene.Nant@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/05</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>Nant
FirstName: Irene
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities</Organization>
    <Organization>Truck Driver
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Irene.Nant</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_36</docID>
    <docDate>9/2/88</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Morluniau
FirstName: Cecilia
BirthDate: 9/2/88
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 9/2/88
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 4/30/09
email: Cecilia.Morluniau@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/08</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities</Organization>
    <Organization>Truck Driver
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>Cecilia
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Cecilia.Morluniau</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Morluniau
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_35</docID>
    <docDate>10/9/84</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Morlun
FirstName: Adan
BirthDate: 10/9/84
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 10/9/84
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 1/14/06
email: Adan.Morlun@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/05</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities</Organization>
    <Organization>Truck Driver
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>Adan
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Adan.Morlun</Person>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Morlun
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_34</docID>
    <docDate>9/22/81</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Morlun
FirstName: Valeria
BirthDate: 9/22/81
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 9/22/81
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 12/2/03
email: Valeria.Morlun@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/01</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Location>Valeria.Morlun</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities</Organization>
    <Organization>Truck Driver
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Valeria
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Morlun
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_33</docID>
    <docDate>4/26/64</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Mies Haber
FirstName: Ruscella
BirthDate: 4/26/64
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 4/26/64
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Administration
CurrentTitle: Assistant to Engineering Group Manager
EmploymentStart: 4/2/03
email: Ruscella.Mies.Haber@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/84</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Administration</Organization>
    <Organization>to Engineering Group Manager
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Mies Haber
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>Ruscella
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Ruscella.Mies.Haber</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_32</docID>
    <docDate>11/19/92</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Mies
FirstName: Minke
BirthDate: 11/19/92
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 11/19/92
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart: 5/22/13
email: Minke.Mies@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/11</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthCountry</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>Minke
BirthDate</Organization>
    <Organization>Minke.Mies</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Security</Organization>
    <Organization>Perimeter Control
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Mies
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_31</docID>
    <docDate>9/23/84</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Mies
FirstName: Henk
BirthDate: 9/23/84
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 9/23/84
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 7/12/13
email: Henk.Mies@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/04</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Henk.Mies</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities</Organization>
    <Organization>Truck Driver
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>Henk
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>HonorableDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Mies
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_30</docID>
    <docDate>7/7/91</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Lais
FirstName: Cornelia
BirthDate: 7/7/91
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 7/7/91
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Administration
CurrentTitle: Assistant to Security Group Manager
EmploymentStart: 12/22/11
email: Cornelia.Lais@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/11</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthCountry</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Kronos
CitizenshipBasis</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Administration</Organization>
    <Organization>Security Group Manager
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Person>ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType</Person>
    <Person>Cornelia
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Cornelia.Lais</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Kronos
Gender</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Lais
FirstName</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_3</docID>
    <docDate>4/30/73</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Azada
FirstName: Lars
BirthDate: 4/30/73
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 4/30/73
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 6/1/11
PassportExpiration: 5/31/21
CurrentEmployment: Engineering
CurrentTitle: Engineer
EmploymentStart: 12/1/95
email: Lars.Azada@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: TethanDefenseForceAir
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/95</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>TethanDefenseForceAir
DischargeType</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>Azada
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Lars
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Lars.Azada</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_29</docID>
    <docDate>5/1/76</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Lagos
FirstName: Varja
BirthDate: 5/1/76
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 5/1/76
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 7/7/13
PassportExpiration: 7/6/23
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Badging Office
EmploymentStart: 10/1/06
email: Varja.Lagos@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Lagos
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Office
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Security
CurrentTitle</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Organization>Varja.Lagos</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
    <Person>Varja
BirthDate</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_28</docID>
    <docDate>1/26/80</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Lagos
FirstName: Linda
BirthDate: 1/26/80
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Female
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 1/26/80
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 11/1/09
PassportExpiration: 10/31/19
CurrentEmployment: Administration
CurrentTitle: Assistant to COO
EmploymentStart: 2/1/10
email: Linda.Lagos@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>Administration</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthCountry</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>COO
EmploymentStart:</Organization>
    <Organization>Lagos
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Linda
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Linda.Lagos</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_27</docID>
    <docDate>10/3/84</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Herrero
FirstName: Kanon
BirthDate: 10/3/84
BirthCountry: Tethys
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Tethys
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 10/3/84
PassportCountry: Tethys
PassportIssue: 10/10/08
PassportExpiration: 10/9/18
CurrentEmployment: Security
CurrentTitle: Badging Office
EmploymentStart: 11/20/08
email: Kanon.Herrero@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: 
DischargeType: 
DischargeDate:</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>Badging Office</Organization>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Tethys</Organization>
    <Person>DischargeType: 
DischargeDate</Person>
    <Person>Herrero
FirstName</Person>
    <Person>Kanon
BirthDate</Person>
    <Person>Kanon.Herrero</Person>
    <Person>kronos
MilitaryBranch</Person>
    <Person>Tethys
Gender</Person>
  </document>
  <document>
    <docID>employee_26</docID>
    <docDate>8/13/83</docDate>
    <docSource></docSource>
    <docText>LastName: Hawelon
FirstName: Claudio
BirthDate: 8/13/83
BirthCountry: Kronos
Gender: Male
Citizenship: Kronos
CitizenshipBasis: BirthNation
CitizenStart: 8/13/83
PassportCountry: 
PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
CurrentEmployment: Facilities
CurrentTitle: Truck Driver
EmploymentStart: 3/13/07
email: Claudio.Hawelon@gastech.com.kronos
MilitaryBranch: ArmedForcesOfKronos
DischargeType: GeneralDischarge
DischargeDate: 10/1/03</docText>
    <Location>gastech.</Location>
    <Organization>BirthNation
CitizenStart</Organization>
    <Organization>Hawelon
FirstName</Organization>
    <Organization>PassportIssue: 
PassportExpiration: 
